<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product Strategy on Kieran Kilbride-Singh – Remote Writer and Marketer</title>
    <link>http://remotekieran.com/tags/product-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product Strategy on Kieran Kilbride-Singh – Remote Writer and Marketer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://remotekieran.com/tags/product-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning a mining pool</title>
      <link>http://remotekieran.com/work/miningpool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://remotekieran.com/work/miningpool/</guid>
      <description>Scam or the future? No matter what you think of blockchains and cryptocurrencies it&amp;rsquo;s where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the hype in tech right now. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got the expertise there&amp;rsquo;s money to be made and interesting challenges to overcome. My client had the technical chops needed to jump on the blockchain hype train. Choo choo! 🚂
This is a risky market though. My client wanted to insulate itself from market volatility as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining and launching an API</title>
      <link>http://remotekieran.com/work/launching-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://remotekieran.com/work/launching-api/</guid>
      <description>After a repositioning and double price raise growth had become stagnant for this SaaS product. The low-hanging marketing fruit was eaten and I was working on growth with long-term channels. Long overdue some love from the product team, we set out to find what the product was missing in the eyes of customers and the market.
Step 1: customer research 👀 The product has a diverse set of customers: regular free users, irregular one-off users, regular weekly users, heavy daily users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an analytics SaaS product from scratch</title>
      <link>http://remotekieran.com/work/new-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://remotekieran.com/work/new-saas/</guid>
      <description>The software studio I was working for was trying to move from client revenue to product revenue. The Directors wanted to build a product analytics tool. Problems faced by clients had led them to believe there was a gap in the market.
 I was responsible for defining the requirements for an analytics product as set by the market, devising the go-to-market strategy, and driving initial growth.
 Process I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a five-part process for an end-to-end project like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximising revenue while enhancing customer value</title>
      <link>http://remotekieran.com/work/maximising-revenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://remotekieran.com/work/maximising-revenue/</guid>
      <description>In January 2017 I accepted a product marketing role at a small software studio. The studio wanted to transition from client revenue to product revenue. It already had two products in the market but they were only bringing in a small percentage of revenue.
One of these products had rapidly gained users, seemingly finding product-market-fit in no time. It helped solve a well-defined problem: turning files (CSV, Excel, JSON) into SQL databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>